Abhijit Seth

Product Design & Development Engineer
Tata Consultancy Services
Client: DePuy Synthes
Kolkata

Phone No.: +91-7044947435 Email Id.: abhijitseth1996@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhijit-seth-69a557200

Summary of Qualifications

- 4.5 years of experience in Design and Development of Medical Devices.
- 4 years of experience in Design and Development (Pre-charter to Design Transfer) of Hip Arthroplasty Implants and Instruments for Primary and Revision surgery.
- 2 years of experience in Design for Additive Manufacturing and Reverse Engineering.
- Experience in Quality Management system for Medical Devices.
- Strong team work, decision-making skills with leadership ability and communication skills.
- Experienced in delivery management and coordinating with different stakeholders.

Technical Skills

Concept Generation, Selection and Feasibility analysis	QMS as per ISO 13485 and EUMDR (2017/745)	Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing - ASME Y14.5M 1994/2009
CAD- Siemens NX, Onepsace	DHF Authoring	Tolerance Stack-up/DVW
Design for Functional Prototyping	-Requirements Management	Change Management (Windchill)
Confidence and Functional Testing	-Risk Management (ISO 14971)	Bone segmentation in Mimics
DFM	-Design V&V	Ultimaker S5
DXT	-Useability Experience	FlashForge Guider II
XRT	TTM (Time To Market) approach	Carl Zeiss Comet 5M (Collin3D, GOM)

Professional Experiences

Tata Consultancy Services

December 2018 - Present

Hip R&D – Tray	Design and Development May 2023 to Present
Responsibilities & Assignments	Team Lead and Product Development Engineer, responsible for Redesign of Cases and Trays. Derive Design Inputs from complains and update DHF documentation Coordination with manufacturer for Concept and generation and finalization Driving Modelling and Drafting of concepts generated as per company guidelines. Formulating Acceptance Criteria Worst-case/Tolerance stack-up Drop and Transit Test PLM activities using Windchill
Achievements	Promotion

Hip R&D – Fem	Hip R&D – Femoral Implant development January 2021 to April 2	
Responsibilities & Assignments	Team Lead and Product Development Engineer, was responsible for Implants and Surgical instruments.	driving the development of Femoral
	Working with Marketing Team and design surgeon for requi-	irement gathering

	 Pre-Charter activities including concept generation, selection, Prototyping, confidence testing protocol writing. 	
	Concept refinement	
	• DHF documentation including RTM, DFMEA, Use Specification, Task Use and Error Analysis	
	Risk Management Report, Design V&V protocols and Reports, Calculation Reports, Design	
	Rationale, Gap analysis, Associative Product Review.	
	Guiding Design Team in Modelling, Drafting and GD&T.	
	DFM discussion with supplier	
	Working with different cross-functional team (RA, FEA, IDHF, Bioengineers, Design Quality)	
	for concept and requirement refinement.	
Achievements	Successful Cadaver and sawbone lab with positive feedback in first go.	
	Received best Delivery Management Award in TCS medical devices vertical, Start of the month	
	and quarter for Management of HIP R&D team.	
	TCS Gems from Client nomination for successful completion and delivery of Phase-1 on time	
	and cost.	

Hip R&D – Acet	abular component development	June 2019 to December 2020
Responsibilities & Assignments	Development Engineer, was responsible for design related activities of Fe Instruments and support product development activities as well.	moral Acetabular Implant and
	 Modelling and Drafting of concepts generated as per company gu GD&T application as per ASME Y14.5 2009 Tolerance stack-up XRT, DXT and 3D DXT Lifecycle Testing protocol and report writing Design Calculations PLM activities using Teamcenter 	uidelines.
Achievements	Successful completion of all the deliverable with high quality within time	eline

Designing for Ad	ditive Manufacturing- Tooling & Fixturing Projects (MDD)	June 2019 to December 2019
Responsibilities	Design Engineer, was responsible for making modifications in legacy	y devices as per Design for
& Assignments	Additive Manufacturing.	
Achievements	Successfully customized design of about 4 products for 3D Printing	

Shoulder NPD-	CAD & Print, Verification and Validation	February 2019 to May 2019
Responsibilities	Design Engineer, was responsible for CAD Modelling and drafting in NX and tolerance stack-up	
& Assignments		

Education

Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering (2014-2018) Maulana Abul Kalam Azad University of Technology (West Bengal University of Technology)